Finding aid to the Samantha Lyon Papers. CA.MS.00366
Smith College Archives
Samantha Lyon papers
Samantha Lyon Papers
2004-2008
2007 - 2008
Smith College Archives
Samantha Lyon
CA.MS.00366
0.625 linear feet <<<<<<< HEAD (2 boxes, including 26 DVDs) ======= (2 boxes, 26 DVDs) >>>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22
Samantha L. Lyon, Smith College Class of 2008, was a campus activist and a co-founder of the college Bicycle Kitchen. The collection consists of artifacts, audiovisual materials, class notebooks, exams, and papers from courses taken by Samantha Lyon, correspondence, as well as materials documenting her role in founding the Bicycle Kitchen and other activism.
Biographical / Historical
Samantha L. Lyon was a member of the Smith College Class of 2008. As a Smith undergraduate, Lyon was committed to promoting bicycles as an environmentally responsible form of transportation and as an enjoyable pastime on campus. Along with fellow activists on campus she started a group called the "Bicycle Kitchen," which invites other bike lovers and riders to learn about bikes, safety, maintenance and benefits.
=======
The collection consists of artifacts, audiovisual materials, class notebooks, exams, and papers from courses taken by Samantha Lyon, correspondence, and various ephemera.
Biographical / Historical
Samantha L. Lyon, Class of 2008
>>>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22
Scope and Contents
The collection contains materials describing the activities of Samantha Lyon including materials from courses and extracurricular activities. Specific material pertaining the founding of Smith College's Bicycle Kitchen and its incorporation with the Student Government Association as well as materials related to Ms. Lyon's "Documenting Oral Histories: Activism at Smith" research thesis. Types of materials include photographs, invitations, newspaper clippings, programs, letters, and DVDs.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use with following restrictions on access: Some restrictions apply to the oral history interviews.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers of Samantha Lyon were donated to the College Archives by Samantha Lyon in 2014.
<<<<<<< HEAD Smith College--Students.; ======= >>>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 Smith College -- Alumni and alumnae -- History -- Sources; Smith College -- Students.; Smith College - Social life and customs -- Sources.
- Community Bike Project: correspondence, August 1, 2005- November 1, 2005 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">1)
- Community Bike Project: correspondence, November 1, 2005 - February 1, 2006 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">2)
- Community Bike Project: general, 2005 - 2006 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">3)
- campaigns: climate change, 2005 - 2008 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">4)
- campaigns: college administration, 2005 - 2008 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">5)
- campaigns: food and nutrition, 2005 - 2008 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">6)
- campaigns: LGBT, 2005 - 2008 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">7)
- campaigns: immigration and race, 2005 - 2008 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">8)
- courses: finals, 2004 - 2008 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">9)
- course: papers, 2004 - 2008 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">10)
- general: artifacts, 2004 - 2008 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">11)
- general: publications, 2004 - 2008 (Box 1, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">12)
- "Documenting Oral Histories": general, 2007 - 2008 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">1)
- "Documenting Oral Histories": notebooks, 2007 - 2008 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">2)
- "Documenting Oral Histories": proposal, 2007 - 2008 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">3)
- "Documenting Oral Histories": release forms, 2007 - 2008 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">4)
- "Documenting Oral Histories": thesis, 2007 - 2008 (Box 2, >>>>>> 9513965d9df0c493d3fef1502b8c9358307d0a22 type="folder">5)
- "Documenting Oral Histories": interviews, restrictions apply